Experience 88 minutes of real fear, captured In real time
Silent House is a horror, mystery, drama film directed by Chris Kentis.
Sarah returns with her father and uncle to fix up the family's longtime
summerhouse after it was violated by squatters in the off-season.
As they work in the dark, Sarah begins to hear sounds from
within the walls of the boarded-up building.
Although she barely remembers the place, Sarah senses
the past may still haunt the home.
Sarah, played by Elizabeth Olsen.
John, played by Adam Trese.
Peter, played by Eric Sheffer Stevens.
Sophia, played by Julia Chan.
Little Girl, played by Haley Murphy.
Stalking Man, played by Adam Barnett.
Silent House is a 2011 American independent psychological horror film directed
by Chris Kentis and Laura Lau, and starring Elizabeth Olsen.
The plot focuses on a young woman who is terrorized in her family vacation
home while cleaning the property with her father and uncle.
An English-language remake of the 2010 Uruguayan film, La Casa Muda (lit.
English:The Silent House), which was allegedly based on an actual
incident that occurred in a village in Uruguay in the 1940s.
It is notable for its use of "real time" footage and the manufactured appearance of a
single continuous shot, similar to Alfred Hitchcock's Rope (1948).
The film premiered at the Sundance Film Festival in January 2011 and was subsequently
purchased by Open Road Films and Universal Pictures for distribution.
Silent House premiered in United States theaters on March 9, 2012.
It opened at number 5 at the U.S.
box office, earning $6.6 million during its opening weekend; it would
go on to gross a total of $12.8 million domestically.
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of supernatural, remake,
beer bottle, real time, candelabra.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.